In the previous example,
在前例中
we saw how we can better our visualizations by removing extraneous elements.
我们学习了如何通过移除不相关元素来提升可视化的效果
We can conceptualize this relationship using something called the data-to-ink ratio.
数据墨水比这个概念正是用来定义这种关系的
The data-to-ink ratio was defined in 1983 by Edward Tufte,
1883 年 Edward Tufte 将它定义为
as the ratio of the amount of ink used to describe
图表中用于描述数据的墨水量占
the data to the total amount of ink in the visual.
图表中总墨水的比值
In general, the higher the data-to-ink ratio, the better.
一般而言 数据墨水比的值越高越好
This means that a large amount of the ink in the
这意味着图表中的大部分墨水
visual is being used to actually describe the data,
是被用来描述实际数据的
while low data-ink ratio suggests that you are using
如果数据墨水比很低 则表明你的大部分墨水
ink that is added for other purposes rather than describing the data.
拿来实现其他的目的 而不是用来描述数据
These elements should be removed.
这些元素应该被剔除
Let's take a look at an example.
我们现在看一个例子
Here, we have two graphs that are representing the same information.
这里 我们有两张图 它们展示了同样的信息
On the left, we have a visualization with low data-to-ink ratio.
左侧是低数据墨水比的图
Notice the extra elements in the visualization that can
能注意到 这图里可以被移除的额外元素
be removed including the blue background,
包括这个蓝色背景、
the horizontal and vertical grid lines,
水平与垂直网格线、
and the outer black border.
以及图表外层的黑色边界
A large amount of the ink in this visualization is not used to describe the data.
在这个图里 有大量墨水没有被用来描述数据
On the right, we see a visualization with
我们再看右侧的图表
the same data but with a high data-to-ink ratio.
它展示了相同的数据 但数据墨水比更高
The visual on the right only has ink used to
这里的墨水主要用在了
directly relate to the understanding of the data.
能提升对数据理解力的地方
Comparing both visualizations, the one on the right is not only more
比较两张可视化图形 右图不仅赏心悦目
pleasing to the eye but it is also much easier to understand.
也更容易理解
When we're building data visualizations,
在设计数据可视化的时候
we always want to strive for a high data-ink ratio.
我们应尽可能地提高数据墨水比
Let's go through a few more examples on how we can
我们再来看几个其他的例子
take a visualization with low data-to-ink ratio,
看看我们如何改进低数据墨水比的图表
or extraneous elements, and reduce it down to
比如移除不相关的元素
something that is much simpler and easier to understand.
使图表能够更方便地被理解
In this example, we're going to take
在这个例子里 我们将想办法提高
a visualization and try to improve its data-to-ink ratio.
图表的数据墨水比
Here, we have a bar chart representing the number of calories for various types of foods.
这是一张展示不同食物卡路里值的条形图
At first glance, we can see examples of
乍看上去 这个图表包含了
bad visualization techniques that we've discussed previously,
我们之前讨论过的不良     可视化元素
such as the busy background,
例如繁杂的背景、
the poor color choices,
糟糕的颜色选择、
and the use of 3D gradients.
以及 3D 条状的应用
Let's walk through it step by step as to how we can simplify
我们现在逐步分析
this visualization and increase its data-to-ink ratio.
评估如何简化这一可视化      并提高其数据墨水比
First, let's remove the wood background from
首先 让我们     移除上面的     黄色背景
the outside and this gray background from the inside,
再     移除内部的灰色背景
increasing contrast and legibility.
提高对比度与易读性
We can also remove redundant labels such as this legend from the titles.
我们还可以剔除冗余的标签 比如 y 轴的标签
This information is encoded elsewhere.
因为这一信息可以从标题上获得
Now that we have removed the backgrounds,
一旦移除了背景
the heavy borders separating the various elements are no longer necessary.
这个黑色边界线也就显得没那么必要了
So let's take those out too.
所以 我们也把它給移除
Remember our coloring theory.
还记得我们的着色理论吗
We shouldn't use more than one or two colors in
一张可视化图形中 颜色不应该超过两种
a visualization unless it's encoded some value in the data.
除非这些颜色承载了数据本身的一些信息
The color of these bars don't reflect any differences between the different foods.
这些条形的颜色无法反映不同食物之间的任何差别
So let's remove those colors as well,
因此 我们也移除这些颜色
except for the food of interest.
除了你感兴趣的食物
In this case, bacon.
在这里就是培根
Great. We've already improved
很棒 我们已经多少改善了图表的数据墨水比
the data-to-ink ratio quite a bit but there's more that we can do.
但我们可以做的更好
Recall that 3D graphs including gradients and shadowing can be misleading.
还记得我们说过 包含梯度和阴影在内的 3D 图形会有误导性
So let's flatten out these bars and remove the drop shadows to make it more clear.
我们拉平这些条形并移除阴影以使之更加清晰
We can also make the data stand out by
我们还可以通过淡化标签
reducing the boldness of these labels and grid lines.
和网格线使得数据更为突出
If we want to go even further,
如果想做的更好
we can remove the lines entirely and encode the label
我们还可以移除所有线条并直接
values directly into the bars, like this.
将标签数值写入到条形里 就像这样
Comparing the two visualization side by side,
比较两边的可视化图形
you can easily see the effect of improving the data-to-ink ratio.
你很容易就看出提高数据墨水比之后的效果
The visualization with the high data-to-ink ratio is far more clear,
具有高数据墨水比的图表要清晰的多
more interpretable, and has all the elements you need for a great visualization.
也更易解读 同时包含了所有能够实现良好可视化的元素